Guide to the Charleston S.C. Typographical Union 43 Records, 1901-1976
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Charleston S.C. Typographical Union 43 records 1901-1976
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Charleston Typographical Union 43 (Charleston, S.C.)
4.4 Linear Feet 2912 Items
Trade-union for the printing industry.
The Charleston S.C. Typographical Union 43 collection consists of correspondence with other local unions; printed material authored by the Charleston Typographical Union No. 43, the International Typographical Union, and the Virginia-Carolina Typographical Conference; and volumes, including minute books, an account book, printed books of laws, and a 1958 convention program. This collection also inludes subject files on such topics as arbitration, arbitration cases, contract negotiations, contracts, newspaper negotiations, resolutions, and secretary-treasurer of the International Typographical Union. These subject files sometimes include correspondence.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charleston Typographical Union 43 (Charleston, S.C.) records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1985.
Historical Note
The Charleston Typographical Union 43 was a trade-union for the printing industry.
Collection Overview
The records of the Charleston Typographical Union Local 43 consist of correspondence with other locals; printed material authored by Local 43, the International Typographical Union, and the Virginia-Carolina Typographical Conference; and volumes relating to the union's activities, including minute books, an account book, printed books of laws, and a 1958 convention program. The collection also inludes subject files on such topics as arbitration, arbitration cases, contract negotiations, contracts, newspaper negotiations, resolutions, and secretary-treasurer of the International Typographical Union. These subject files sometimes include correspondence. There is also some oversize material housed separately. Note: collection consists of two components, only one of which is represented by a box list.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Charleston Typographical Union 43 (Charleston, S.C.)
International Typographical Union
Virginia-Carolina Typographical Conference
Printing industry -- Employees -- Political activity
Printing industry -- South Carolina -- Charleston
Printing industry -- Employees -- Labor unions
Labor unions -- Records
Labor unions -- South Carolina -- Charleston
Related Material
Raleigh N.C. International Typographical Union Local 54 Records, 1921-1948
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Description of Collection
- Original Records, 1886-1953, (10 boxes; 2,286 items)
  Originally part of the Labor Archives collection, the original set of records of the Charleston Typographical Union 43 include correspondence and reports, primarily of the various persons who served as secretary-treasurer of Local 43, discussing arbitration, a ten per cent assessment on earnings of union members to promote the 44-hour week, wages, strike benefits and contributions, conventions, membership, dues, and traveling cards; information and reports from the parent organization; account books recording fines and assessments, expenditures, and receipts; minute books; applications for membership and membership and pension rolls; and published materials. There is currently no box list for these records.
  - Charleston Typographical Union Records (Box 9-19)
- Addition (1985), 1901-1976, (11 boxes)
  - Correspondence Series, 1927-1969, (2 boxes)
    Series includes correspondence with other locals.
    - Correspondence, 1927-1968 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1969 (Box 2)
  - Printed Material Series, 1901-1971, (3 boxes)
    Includes yearbooks, conference bulletins, union pamphlets, and publications.
    - Printed Material (Box 2)
    - Printed Material (Box 3)
    - Printed Material (Box 5)
  - Volumes Series, 1938-1975, (3 boxes)
    Series includes minute books, account books, convention programs, and other union bound volumes.
    - Minute Books, 1938-1947 (Box 3)
    - Minute Books, 1950-1975 (Box 4)
    - Account Book (Box 5)
    - Book of Laws (Box 5)
  - Subject Files Series, (6 boxes)
    Series organized alphabetically as in original arrangement.
    - Ant-Arbitration Cases (Box 6)
    - Arbitration Cases-Contract Negotiations (Box 7)
    - Contract Negotiations-Contracts (Box 8)
    - Delegate Reports-Newspaper Negotiations (Box 9)
    - Newspapers-Scale Negotiations (Box 10)
    - Secretary-Walker (Box 11)